Mss.Ms.Coll.56
American Philosophical Society
- XVI. Aerial Photographs of Canyonbound Rivers, 1964-1965; 2.0 Linear feet 6 boxes; 818 photos
  - Group 6. Colorado River, Arizona. Grand Canyon. Ca. Mile 209, 1965 May 11 (Box 57)
    12 photos; 1965 May 11
- XVII. Photographs (prints and negatives), 1938-2004; 2.0 Linear feet (Box 58-62)
  Series XVII, Photographs and Negatives, is not processed at this time; thus box numbers are not assigned although folders have been created to hold groups of photos as found grouped in Luna Leopold's papers.
  Photos are mixed professional and personal content. Folders contain photo packages as grouped by Leopold; his annotations on envelopes and packages are recorded here. There is no separate catalog or record other than his annotations. Numerous photos have no specific identifications other than Leopold's general annotation for the whole roll of film or groups of films.
  APS does not at this time hold digitized images of photos from the Luna B. Leopold Papers, nor are there photographic prints of the negatives except those that were received from Leopold. Some folders thus contain only negatives, which have not either been printed or digitized at this time. The collection has no digital imagery as created by or received by Leopold; everything is in the form of negatives and prints.
  Photos will also be found throughout the Luna B. Leopold Papers. Those that accompanied correspondence, or which Leopold included with research and reference files, among other kinds of files, will be found with those items. Scope and Content notes for pertinent files that include photos indicate which among them have such material.
  - Arizona, 1970
    Annotations: "Road cut rear Tucson 1970" (b/w prints; 4x5-inch copy negatives, color and b/w). "Newman Peak, Phoenix 1970" (two rolls 35-mm negatives, b/w, uncut).
  - Arroyo de los Frijoles; Big Sweat Dam, 1974 (Box 58)
    Annotation: "Arroyo Frijoles--Santa Fe 1974 Big Sweat Dam Roll 7 1974". B/w prints and 4x5-in. b/w copy negatives
  - Arroyo de los Frijoles; Chamisa Arroyo; Rio Cundayo, 1974 (Box 58)
    Annotation: "Arroyo Frijoles Chamisa Arroyo Rio Cundayo Santa Fe 1974 Roll 6 1974". B/w Prints and 4x5-inch b/w copy negatives.
  - Arroyo de los Frijoles Project; New Mexico; Hawaii, 1958; 1961; 1962; undated
    Filed under "Arroyo Frijoles". Annotations: "Arroyo Frijoles Project July August Santa Fe 1961" (two 2-2/4 x 2-1/4-in b/w negatives). "1962 Sisters rill; Frijoles Arroyo" (one 2-2/4 x 2-1/4-in b/w negative). "New Mexico August 1958" (2-2/4 x 2-1/4-in b/w negatives). "Slopes: Hawaii", undated (one 2-2/4 x 2-1/4-in b/w negative).
  - Arroyo de los Frijoles Project; North Fork Popo Agie River; No Grub Slope; Bald Mountain Slope, 1963 August
    Annotation: "Frijoles Project N Fk Popo Agie No Grub Slope Bald Mt Slope Aug 1963". 1 roll b/w 35-mm negatives, uncut
  - Artwork Photos, 1984
    Four color prints; annotated. [N.B.: "BCL" = Bruce C. Leopold; "NSL" = Nina S. Leopold.]
  - Bagnold, Ralph A., family, 1958
    Ralph A. Bagnold and two women. Annotation: "For Bagnold Bagnold family". One 35mm color transparency with October 1958 processing date, and color negative made from transparency.
  - Baldwin Creek, Wyoming; Seneca Creek, Watts Branch, Maryland, 1959
    Annotations: "Baldwin Creek, Lander Wyo June 1959"; "Baldwin Creek, wyo, Junee 1959 Seneca Creek, Md. Spring 59". B/w negatives. "Watts Br. Sisters Baldwin Cr. Frijoles Arroyo. Mar-June 1959". B/w negatives, uncut.
  - Bridger National Forest Clear Cutting Bedload Project, 1974 September
    Annotation: "Bridger Forest clear cutting Sept 1974 Bedload prioject Roll 2 1974". Eight b/w prints and negatives.
  - California; Eel River; Redwoods, 1973
    Annotation: "Many of the negatives are in this packet. California Eel R Redwoods. Roll 1-3 1973". B/w copy negatives, and three b/w prints.
  - Canada, 1938
    Annotation: "Canada 1938 Xmas card negatives". Four b/w negatives.
  - Chaco Canyon, Bridger National Forest, 1974
    Annotation: "Small tributary after flood near Caco Canyon Bridger forest clear cut Roll 3 1974". Ten b/w prints, and negatives.
  - Ditch Creek, 1998 July 28
    Annotation: Ditch Creek--new channel July 28, 1998". One color print.
  - East Fork River; Red Butte Hill, 1980
    Annotation: "East fork clear cuts Red Butte Hill Roll 5". Five b/w prints, and negatives.
  - East fork River; Takayama, Shigemi; Family photos, 1980
    Annotation: "4 of Carrie at graduation 1980 East Fork in flood & later 1980 Prof Takayama t forest site Roll 2". Sixteen b/w prints (none are family); and negatives
  - Garcia River; Trinity River, 1995 February
    Color prints, each annotated on verso (not by Leopold).
  - Garcia River; Kidder Creek, 1995 February-March
  - Greece, 1958
    Annotations: "Greece 1958"; "Christmas Greece 1958". B/w negatives.
  - Greek Islands, 1993
    Annotation: "No 26". Five color prints, each annotated by Leopold on verso; four color negatives.
  - Green River, Utah; Sunflower Leaves Entropy Study, 1962
    Annotation: "Green River Utah Sunflower leaves Entropy Study 1962". One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Horse Creek, 1974; Greenhorn Mountains, Sierra Nevada, 1975, 1974-1975
    Annotations: "1974 Horse Creek"; "1974 Greenhorn Mts--Sierra Nevada". Twelve b/w prints.
  - Israel, 1974
    Annotation: "Israel 1974 Roll 1 1974". Eight b/w prints, and negatives.
  - Israel; Marin County, California; Pinedale lakes, Wyoming, 1974
    Annotation: "Israel Marin County Pinedale lakes Roll 1A 1974". Eighteen b/w prints.
  - Italy, 1996 May
    Annotation: "Itally--May 1996". Color negatives.
  - Leopold, Barbara (Mrs. Luna B. Leopold), 1998
    Not annotated; theatrical production(?). One color print.
  - Leopold, Bruce, 1962
    Annotation: "Bruce graduation 1962". B/w negatives.
  - Leopold, Bruce [family]; Aerial Photographs of Desert [professional], 1963 April 25
    Annotation: "4/25/63 Bruce, Cristy M Plane photos of west desert." One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Leopold, Luna B. Folder 1, 1975; [1980]; 2003; undated
    B/w and color prints. Includes professional portraits.
  - Leopold, Luna B. Folder 2, 1960
    Annotation: "LBL at Frijoles 1960" [Arroyo Frijoles]. Two b/w negatives.
  - Leopold, Madelyn, 1963
    Annotation: "Madelyn Georgia (Grass mama) 1963". One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Monument Valley; Mexican Springs, 1995
    Annotation: "Mexican Spgs. Monument Valley". Color prints, and negatives.
  - Nature Photos, undated
    One color print, annotated (not by Leopold); pair of sandhill cranes in Wyoming.
  - New Fork River; Silver Creek; East Fork River; Santa Fe; Fontinelle, 1974
    Annotation: "New Fk at Boulder Silver Cr East Fk at Hwy 353 Santa Fe Fonintelle Roll 5 1974". Seven b/w prints, and negatives.
  - Nepal/India 1971; Russia 1962; Salmon River, Idaho, 1962; 1971; undated
    B/w prints and negatives; mixed.
  - New Mexico; Arizona; Colorado, 1994
    Annotations: "Douglas Creek", "Shell Section"; "Puerco" [Rio Puerco]. Two b/w contact sheets.
  - New Zealand, North Island, 1970
    Annotations: "1970 N Island, NZ Waiapoa R" [two envelopes]; "1970 New Zealand N Island wood carving". B/w negatives.
  - Paris, 1967; Popo Agie River, Wyoming, 1963, 1963 May; 1967 June
    Annotation: "Paris, May 1967 Wyoming, June '67, flood of Popo Agie 1963". One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - People--Family 1959
    Annotation: "Family 1959"; not identified. Two b/w negatives.
  - People--Family 1964-1965
    Annotation: "Family 1964-5"; not idetified. B/w negatives.
  - People--Family; Family(?), 1982; undated
    Color prints; some annoated on verso (not by Leopold); and color and b/w negatives.
  - People--Professional, undated
    Annotations: "Photos of John PM (field portraits)"; "Myrick & Dury". Three b/w prints, and b/w negatives.
  - People--Unidentified; Locations Known, 1967
    Annotation: "Circle S Ranch Pinedale, 1967" [Pinedale, Wyoming]. B/w copy negatives.
  - People--Identified; Location Undetermined, 1993
    Annotation: "Dave Love 1993" [photo includes Mrs. Barbara Leopold]. Color print.
  - People--Unidentified; Locations Undetermined, undated
    B/w formal portraits and color print.
  - Pinedale, Wyoming, 1966 Summer
    Annotation: "Pinedale Summer 1966"; mixed family(?), professional. One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Pinedale, Wyoming; Horse Creek. Greenhorn Mountains, Sierra Nevada., 1974-1975
    Annotation: "1974-75 Pinedale--Horse Creek--August 74 Sierra Nevada--Greenhorn Mts." B/w negatives.
  - Places--Not Professional, 1998; undated
    Two color prints (one annotated on verso, not by Leopold).
  - Places--Professional; Not Identified [Israel?], 1974
    One b/w print; processing date 1974 February 26.
  - Places--Professional; Not Identified, 1980
    Annotations: "Roll 2" [Seven b/w prints at one stream locality, and negatives] "Roll 6" [Low-altitude b/w prints, aerial views from single-engine aircraft; and negatives] Both store envelopes noted, "USGS Emmett 9/25/80".
  - Places--Professional; Not Identified, 1996, 2004
    Color laser-print photos on paper.
  - Places--Professional; Not Identified; Undated
    B/w prints, and negatives.
  - Places--Professional (Wyoming?), 2000, 2000 July
    Annotation: "July 2000 1st film with Vita Finzi" [Claudio Vita-Finzi]. Color prints, and negatives.
  - Popo Agie River (Lander, Wyoming), 1961 June
    Annotation: "Popo Agie 1961 June (Lander Wyo)". One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Popo Agie River, North Fork, 1963
    Annotation: "N Fk Popo Agie 1963". Seven b/w prints, and negatives.
  - "Prints For Publication", 1970-1971; undated
    B/w prints, and negatives. Annotations: "1971 Nepal Valleys and mountains from plane" "India--Stone screens" "Kenya--Hillslopes in Nairobi on road to Bombasa" "Tokushima: Rivers on Shikoku, Japan 1970" "Japan 1970 Tokushima--Rivers gaging station" "Japan--river checkdams, N[orth] Island New Zealand erosion & gullies" "Kenya I[illegible] Lodge Namburu Hillsclope on Badlands"; "Greece with friends"; "Israel Hillslopes at Mt. Sodom" "1971 Israel Nahal Yarl hillslopes" "1971 Israel Hillslopes at Nahal Yarl; Valletys in Negeve; Walls at Advat"
  - Pueblo Bonito, 1995
    Annotation: "Pueblo Bonito". Three color prints, and negatives; processing date July 1995.
  - Rio Puerco, 1995
    Annotation: "Rio Puerco". Color prints, and negatives; processing date July 1995.
  - Rio Puerco Station, 1995
    Annotation: "Luna B Leopold Rio Puerco Station"; processing date July 1995. Color prints, and negatives.
  - Russia, 1962
    Annotations: "A Russia 1962"; "B August 1962 Russia Summarkand Tashkent Bruce [Leopold] & family". Two rolls b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Sage Hen; Prosser Creek, 1973
    Annotation: "Sage Hen--Prosser Cr--1973". Ten b/w prints, and negatives.
  - Salmon River, Idaho, 1966 July
    Annotations: "C Idaho July 66"; "Salmon River Idaho Leopold July 66". One roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Santa Fe Ana; Arroyo Frijoles; Arroyo Falta, 1974
    Annotation: "Santa Fe Ana Arroyo Frijoles Arroyo Falta 1974 Roll 8 1974". Fifteen b/w prints, and negatives.
  - Santa Fe Urbanization, 1974
    Annotation: "Santa Fe urbanization Ar[royo] Frijoles near Tsegi Marsh pass rills on sandstone hill Deposition behind dam at Ramah NM. Roll 4 1974". Seven b/w prints, and negatives.
  - Seneca Creek, 1954-1959
    All filed under "Seneca Creek". Annotations: "Seneca Creek in flood 1954"; b/w negatives. "Seneca Cr. flood 1954 low flow 1959?"; b/w negatives. "Seneca Cr 1955"; b/w negatives. "Family; Seneca Cr. Winter 1958-59"; one roll b/w negatives, uncut.
  - Switzerland, Glacier Streams, 1960
    Filed under "Glacier Streams". Annotations: "Suisee--glacier 1960"; "Glacier Suessi [sic] 1960". B/w negatives.
  - Tsegi Arroyo; Douglas Creek, 1995
    Annotation: "Tsegi Arroyo Rangelog--Douglas Cr."; processing date July 1995. Color prints, and negatives.
  - "Useful Photos", 1955; undated
    Seven b/w prints, contact sheet, and negatives.
  - Vigil Network [U.S. Geological Survey], Rio Chaco, Chaco Canyon National Monument, 1961 August
    Annotation: "Cross section of Tributary Rio chaco, Chaco Natl Mon. Aug 1961 Vigil Network. Leopold". One b/w print; two negatives.
  - Vigil Sites [U.S. Geological Survey], 1963 July-August
    Annotations: "Wind R Mts. N. Fork Popo Agie R. Wyo July 1963". "Wind R. N. Fork Popo Agie July 1963". "Midden Rock, 4 Corners N.M. Aug 1963". Three rolls b/w negatives, uncut.
- XVIII. Films, 0.25 Linear feet 1 box
  Series XVIII contains a reel of motion-picture film and two reels of microfilm, as described.
  - Green River [Utah]. 16-mm color film, silent, [? 1965 October]; 1.0 Film reel(s) (Box 63)
    Images depict research trip on the Green River, Utah [probably October 1965]. 1 reel (approx. 100 ft.) 16 mm motion-picture film; no sound. Format undetermined: Kodachrome II film type; "62" is noted along the edge; frame size 11 x 7.5 mm; two rows of sprocket holes, which on one side encroach into the images.
  - Microfilm Reels [1] and [2]. Velocity Profiles, Grand Canyon [Colorado River] and Lake Mead, Arizona-Nevada, 2.0 Microfilm reel(s) (Box 63)
- XIX. Plane Table Maps, 1950-1986; 2.0 box 2 boxes (oversize); 119 items (Box OS-2, OS-3)
  Series XIX (Oversize) comprises a set of 119 plane table maps by Leopold and others, from work conducted in the American West and Northeast.
  Uniform, generalized titles are shown in the list. Scope and Contents Notes for each map quote map titles as actually written on maps, along names of the mapping teams.
  Maps are arranged in chronological order to facilitate use with Leopold's Field Notes (Series XI); they were not in any particular arrangement when received by APS. Arranging maps in geographical order was imprudent due to the inclusion of multiple locales on some maps.
  - 1. Undated [1965 June]. Colorado River at Papago Creek, Grand Canyon, Arizona
    "Rapids at Papago Creek, Grand Canyon". [June 1965]. [Leopold].
  - 2. Undated. Clear Creek, Wyoming
    "Clear Creek near Ucross (Copps Ranch—now 'Ike' Thomas' Ranch)".
  - 3. Undated. Sunmount Arroyo
    "Sunmount Arroyo, High water marks of July 3 flow". Map overlaid by graph paper with plots.
  - 4. Undated. Wind River, Wyoming
    "Dumb Cowboy Reach of Wind River above Dubois, Wyoming, showing channel geometry after Meander Cutoff (high flows of June, 1965)". Emmett, Parkes.
  - 5. Undated. Lance Creek, Laramie River, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Oil Well Draw, Lance Creek".
    Side 2: "Typical Section No. 1, Laramie River [near Wheatland]". With inset "Location Map".
  - 6. 1950 July 15. Lance Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: [Map 1] "Drainage #1, Lance Creek Watershed"; Leopold, Miller. [Map 2] "Typical Terrace Relations, Lower Lance Creek Site 1, ± 3/4 mile upstream from Drainage #1 Lance Creek shown on this sheet." [Map 3] "Typical Terrace Relations, Lower Lance Creek Site 2, located ± 3/4 mile upstream from Site 1, this sheet."
    Side 2: [Map 1] "Typical Section Lance Creek, No. 3, 5 miles by road above Sect. 2"; Leopold, Miller. [Map 2] "Typical Sect 4 (Tick Bend) (2.8 miles by road above Sect. 3)." [Map 3] "Drainage 2, Old Field (Lance)"; "discontinuous gully".
  - 7. 1950 July 15-16. Lance Creek, Belle Fourche, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Artifact Cienaga or Section 4, Upper Lance Creek"; 1950 July 15.
    Side 2: [Map 1] "Terrace Profile, Belle Fourche at Moorcroft, Wyoming", 1950 July 16; Leopold, Miller; with inset location map. [Map 2] "Belle Fourche below Carlisle, Wyoming"; 1950 July 16; Miller, Leopold.
  - 8. 1950 July 16-17. Neardark Gully, Powder River, Wyoming
    Side 1: [Map 1] "Neardark Gully, Powder River 1/2 mile E of Arvada Road Jct."; undated; with inset Location Map. [Map 2] "Powder River at Bulkley Ranch, 11.4 miles by road N of Highway 16 and about 16 miles N of Arvada, Wyoming"; 1950 July 17; Miller, Leopold.
    Side 2: [Map 1] "Powder River above Arvada"; 1950 July 16 or 17; Miller, Leopold; with insets, "Replot of Data off Map" and "Location Map". [Map 2] "Powder River at Arvada Jct. Bridge where Highway 16 crosses Powder River and 5 miles N of Arvada, Wyoming"; 1950 July 17; Miller, Leopold. With notes on map: "Area of crude artifacts on terrace top", "Site of Pleistocene congeliturbation; frost crack or ice wedge filling, mammoth tooth, and limonitic soil on top of old pediment surface".
  - 9. 1950 July 17-18. Powder River, Wyoming
    Side 1: [Map] "Rainedout Gully near Arvada, Wyoming"; 1950 July 17; Miller, Leopold; with inset Location Map. [Sketch] "Congeliturbate, Powder River Bridge at Arvada Jct." [detailed sketch of exposure].
    Side 2: [Map 1] "Congeliturbate Site at Powder River Bridge, Arvada Jct., Wyoming [map]"; undated; Miller, Leopold. [Map 2] "Gullies Graded to Middle Terrace mapped to indicate rejuvenation of old gullies, near Arvada, Wyoming"; 1950 July 18; Leopold, Miller; with inset Location Map.
  - 10. 1950 July 19. Hasta Luego Wash, Montana
    "Hasta Luego Wash near Billings, Montana"; Leopold, Miller; includes inset Location Map.
  - 11. 1950 July 20. Big Horn River, Little Bighorn River, Montana, 1950 July 20; undated
    Side 1: "Bighorn River at Hardin Bridge (Highway 87), Montana"; 1950 July 20; Miller, Leopold; with inset Location Map. Noted on map: "Soil Sample Site 1", and "Sml Samples of fossil soil taken here, in cliff face".
    Side 2: "Little Big Horn River near Lodge Grass, Montana (Highway 87 ca. 4 miles from Lodge Grass)"; undated; with inset Location Map.
  - 12. 1950 August 22. Revision Draw, Twenty Mile Creek, Wyoming
    "Revision Draw and Twenty Mile Creek, Wyoming; Sec 14 T35N R67W, 12 miles W of Lance Creek Village"; Leopold, Hembree. With pencilled perspective sketch of site and cross section along channel bed.
  - 13. 1951 July 12. Hat Creek Gully, Belle Fourche, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Profile and Traverse, Hat Creek Gully, Wyoming"; Leopold, Miller.
    Side 2: "Cross-section Belle Fourche at Highway 59 about 30 miles S of Gillette, Wyoming."
  - 14. 1951 July 21. Clear Creek, Wyoming
    "Clear Creek and Tributary, 1 mile E of Buffalo, Wyoming"; Leopold, Roach.
  - 15. 1952 June 21. Baldwin Creek, Wyoming
    "Meander No. 1, Lander, Wyoming, Baldwin Creek 100 ft below Highway 287 bridge"; Leopold, Miller.
  - 16. 1952 June 21. Baldwin Creek, Wyoming, 1952 June 21; 1959 June 13
    "Baldwin Creek 1 mile N of Lander, Wyoming; 1952 June 21; Leopold, Miller. Traverse and elevation continued 1959 June 13"; Myrick, Leopold.
  - 17. 1952 June 29. Arroyo Falta, New Mexico
    "Arroyo Falta, on road to Las Dos near Santa Fe, New Mexico"; Leopold, Miller. Annotation in red ink: "Stationing inserted 1963 to approx. that of July 14 1962 map".
  - 18. 1952 July 5. Fifth of July Wash, New Mexico
    "5th of July Wash, on W side of road to San Juan Ranch, 3 miles N of Santa Fe, New Mexico"; Leopold, Miller.
  - 19. 1952 July 9. San Cristobal Arroyo, New Mexico
    "San Cristobal Arroyo at old ruin 6 miles S of Lamy, New Mexico"; Leopold, Miller.
  - 20. 1952 July 20. Sandia Pediment, New Mexico
    Side 1: "Profile of Sandia Pediment"; Leopold, Miller.
    Side 2: "Sandia Pediment, 2.3 miles N of Highway 66".
  - 21. 1952 July 26. San Cristobal Ruin, Canada Ancho, New Mexico
    Side 1: "San Cristobal Ruin"; Leopold,Miller.
    Side 2: "Water surface slope, Arroyo near Euler Ranch (Canada Ancho)".
  - 22. 1952 December 16. Buck Run, Pennsylvania
    "Pool and Riffle, Buck Run, 300 yards upstream from confluence with Doe run, Brandywine River Basin, Doe Run, Pennsylvania"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 23. 1952 December 17. Valley Creek [Downingtown, Pennsylvania]
    "Valley Creek, opposite Sugaridge Farm (Shenton barn)"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 24. 1953 March 20. Watts Branch, Maryland
    "Watts Branch at Viers Ranch"; Leopold, Vice, Wolman.
  - 25. 1953 July 15. MIddle River, Virginia
    Side 1: "Middle River near Bethlehem Church S of Staunton, Virginia".
    Side 2: [Map depicting Cristians Creek at Orange Bridge and Barter Brook.]
  - 26. 1953 July 17. South River, Edison Creek, Virginia., 1953 July 17; undated
    [Map 1] "Black Bull Reach of South River near Mt. Vernon Church"; Wolman, Leopold. [Map 2] "Edison Creek at New Spring"; undated.
  - 27. 1953 August 8, 12. New Fork River, Wyoming
    "New Fork 200 yards S of Jenkins Ranch and 2 miles N of Cora, Wyoming"; Rubey, Leopold, Wolman. Noted on map: "Cabin abandoned for obvious reasons".
  - 28. 1953 August 10. Horse Creek, Wyoming, 1953 August 10; 1956 July 8
    [Map 1] "Horse Creek at Gaging Station west of Daniel, Wyoming"; Leopold, Wolman. [Map 2] "Remapped July 8, 1956."
  - 29. 1956 August 10-11. Duck Creek, Cottonwood Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Meanders of Duck Creek near Cora, Wyoming, 1 mile by road from Cora"; 1953 August 10; Leopold, Wolman.
    Side 2: "Cottonwood Creek at gaging station near Daniel, Wyoming"; 1953 August 11; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 30. 1953 August 12. Green River, Wyoming
    "The Horsefly Reach, Green River at Daniel, Wyoming"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 31. 1953 August 12. New Fork River, Wyoming
    "The American Gothic Reach of New Fork River 3.4 miles below Pinedale, Wyoming"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 32. 1953 August 15. Du Noir Creek, Wind River, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Du Noir Creek 1 mile above mouth"; Leopold, Wolman. Note on map: "1st farm yard upstream from mouth on this side".
    Side 2: "The Dumb Cowboy Reach, Wind River above Du Noir Creek"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 33. 1953 August 16-17. Popo Agie River, Wyoming.
    "Joyful Reach of the Popo Agie River 1/2 mile below Hudson, Wyoming"; "The River Boys" Leopold, Wolman; with penciled musical notes and fish.
  - 34. 1953 August 17. Squaw Creek, Wyoming
    "Squaw Creek 1 1/2 miles W of Lander, Wyoming"; Leopold, Miller.
  - 35. 1953 September 11. Little Pipe Creek, Maryland
    "Little Pipe Creek above Avondale gage near Westminster, Maryland"; [L.] Leopold, Wolman, B. Leopold.
  - 36. 1953 September 23. Watts Branch, Maryland
    "Watts Branch at Viers Ranch"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 37. 1953 October 12. Middle River, Virginia
    "Middle River below Franks Mill near Staunton, Virginia"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 38. 1953 October 13. Middle River, Virginia
    "Middle River below Franks Mill"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 39. 1954 July 19. Seneca Creek, Maryland
    "Seneca Creek near Dawsonville, Maryland"; Leopold, Wolman; on reinforced board manufactured by Glassoloid Corp.
  - 40. 1954 August 10. New Fork River, Boulder Creek, Pine Creek, Wyoming, 1954 August 10; undated
    Side 1: "American Gothic Reach, New Fork River"; Leopold, Wolman; with pencil sketches of cloud and mosquito. 1954 August 10.
    Side 2: "Boulder Creek below Boulder Lake"; "Pole Creek near Pinedale, Wyoming". Undated.
  - 41. 1954 August 11, 13. Middle Piney Creek, Horse Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Horse Creek at gage"; Leopold, Wolman. 1954 August 11.
    Side 2: "Middle Piney Creek at gage 18 miles NW of Big Piney, Wyoming"; Leopold, Wolman. 1954 August 13.
  - 42. 1954 August 14-15. Big Sandy River, Little Sandy River, wyoming
    Side 1: "The Big Sandy at Leckie Ranch"; Leopold, Wolman; with pencil sketch of flower. 1954 August 14.
    Side 2: "Little Sandy at crossing of Lander Trail near Big Sandy Opening, 'known by the prosaic surf. water br. [Surface Water Branch, USGS] as Little Sandy near Elkhorn, Wyoming' "; Leopold, Wolman. 1954 August 15.
  - 43. 1954 August 15. Hams Fork, and Green River, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Hams Fork near Frontier (Ugh!)"; Leopold, Wolman.
    Side 2: "Green River near Fontenelle at gage"; Leopold, Wolman.
  - 44. 1954 August 19, 22. Rock Creek, Montana; Middle Fork of Clear Creek, Wyoming
    Side 1: "Rock Creek above Red Lodge, Montana at gage"; Leopold, Wolman; with pencil sketch of fish on line. 1954 August 19.
    Side 2: "Middle Fork, Clear Creek above Buffalo, Wyoming"; Leopold, Wolman; with pencil sketch of dutch oven. 1954 August 22.